Kotschnig, Walter Maria; Papers ger053
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Organizations, 1936-1975; 3; 67 file folders
  - American Educational Research Association, 1940 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 4)
  - Austrian Action, Free Austrian Movement, 1941-1942 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 5)
  - Austrian-American League, 1941 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 6)
  - Belgian Commission for the Study of Post-War Problems, New York, 1942 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 7)
  - Civilian Rehabilitation Corps / Reconstruction Service Committee, 1942 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 8)
  - The Commission to Study the Organization of Peace, 1941-1944; 1976-1977 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 9)
  - Committee on International Education and Cultural Relations, 1944 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 10)
  - Council for German Jewry, 1937 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 11)
  - European Student Relief Fund, 1940-1941 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 12)
  - European Student Relief Fund, 1942 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 13)
  - European Student Relief Fund, 1943 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 14)
  - Far Eastern Student Emergency Fund. Minutes, 1937-1938 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 15)
  - Far Eastern Student Emergency Fund. Publications, 1938-1940 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 16)
  - German American Congress for Democracy, 1941-1942 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 17)
  - Institute of International Education, Inc., 1950-1951 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 18)
  - Institute on Educational Reconstruction in Central and Eastern Europe (Schairer Committee), 1943 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 19)
  - The Institute on Man and Science, 1975 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 20)
  - Intercollegiate Committee to Aid Student Refugees, 1939; 1952 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 21)
  - International Committee on Intellectual Cooperation and Cultural Relations, 1944 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 22)
  - International Institute of Administrative Sciences, 1952 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 23)
  - International Student Service. Minutes, 1936-1938 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 24)
  - International Student Service. Minutes, 1939 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 25)
  - International Student Service. Minutes, 1940 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 26)
  - International Student Service. Minutes, 1941 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 27)
  - International Student Service. Minutes, 1942 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 28)
  - International Student Service, Refugee Committee / Refugee Scholars Fund, 1940-1944 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 29)
  - International Student Service. Newsletters, 1937 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 30)
  - International Student Service. Newsletters, 1938 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 31)
  - International Student Service. Newsletters, 1939 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 32)
  - International Student Service. Newsletters, 1940 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 33)
  - International Student Service. Newsletters, 1941 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 34)
  - International Student Service. Newsletters, 1942 (Box 9 (3-Organizations), Folder 35)
  - International Student Service. International Student Assembly, 1942 September 02-1942 September 05 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 1)
  - International Student Service. International Students Day, 1942 November 17 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 2)
  - International Student Service. Work Camps for America, 1940 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 3)
  - International Student Service. Publications, 1937-1942; 1970 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 4)
  - International Student Service.I.S.S. Bulletin, 1937-1938 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 5)
  - Liason Committee for International Education. International Education Assembly, 1943 September 13-1943 September 18 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 6)
  - League of Nations. International Institute of Intellectual Cooperation, Paris, 1938 November 03-1938 November 04 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 7)
  - League of Nations Association, Education Committee, 1942-1943 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 8)
  - London International Assembly, 1941-1942 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 9)
  - Loyal Americans of German Descent, 1941-1942 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 10)
  - Masaryk Institute, 1942-1943 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 11)
  - National Committee of the United States of America on International Intellectual Cooperation, 1943 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 12)
  - National Japanese American Student Relocation Council, 1943 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 13)
  - National Student Federation of America, 1938 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 14)
  - National Student Relief Committee. Newsletters, 1943 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 15)
  - Notgemeinschaft deutscher Wissenschaftler im Ausland, 1936-1937 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 16)
  - People's Column for World Democracy, 1941 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 17)
  - Society for the Protection of Science and Learning (formerly Academic Assistance Council), 1936-1937 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 18)
  - Student Service of America, Inc., 1943-1946 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 19)
  - The Workers' Educational Association, 1938-1939 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 20)
  - World's Student Christian Federation and Reconstruction, 1943 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 21)
  - World Student Relief, 1944 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 22)
  - World Student Relief, North American Affiliated Committee, 1943-1944 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 23)
  - World Student Service Fund. Minutes, 1940-1941 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 24)
  - World Student Service Fund. Minutes, 1942 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 25)
  - World Student Service Fund. Minutes, 1943 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 26)
  - World Student Service Fund. Minutes, 1944 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 27)
  - World Student Service Fund. Newsletters, 1940-1943 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 28)
  - World Student Service Fund. Handbooks, 1941-1944 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 29)
  - World Student Service Fund. Personnel file, Undated (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 30)
  - World Student Service Fund. Publications, Undated (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 31)
  - 2nd World Youth Congress, Vassar College, 1938 August 16-1938 August 24 (Box 10 (3-Organizations), Folder 32)
- Manuscripts of speeches and lectures delivered by Walter M. Kotschnig, 1933-1976; Undated; 4; 191 folders
  This series dates predominately from the years 1933-1944, the years when Kotschnig was both on the faculties of Smith and Mt. Holyoke Colleges and also lecturing throughout the country. The lectures are mainly in the form of handwritten notes, with very few actual typewritten texts. Also in this series are course lecture notes from Kotschnig's courses at Smith, Mt. Holyoke and Harvard-Boston University Extension School, 1937-1944.
  - "Antisemitism", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 1)
  - "The Battle for the Mind", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 2)
  - "The Breakdown of the Wilsonian World", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 3)
  - "The Burden and the Promise of Our Age", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 4)
  - "Can Europe Be Re-educated for Democracy?", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 5)
  - "Education in Wartime", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 6)
  - "European Universities menaced by overcrowding", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 7)
  - "I.S.S. & the University of to-day", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 8)
  - "Munich 10th Anniversary, 14/5/3?", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 9)
  - "Nazi Education", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 10)
  - "The Need for a re-orientation in education", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 11)
  - "Overcrowding", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 12)
  - "Racial Issues in Europe", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 13)
  - "The Soul of Young Europe", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 14)
  - "University in a Changing World". Montreal, Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 15)
  - "The World of the Future". Springfield Fonts Club, Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 16)
  - "World Order Through Education", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 17)
  - "The World to-day -- its dangers & possibilities", Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 18)
  - "Significance of Hitler". Toronto, 1933 March 13 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 19)
  - "Wider Horizons". Studio Club, 1933 March 19 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 20)
  - Untitled, Social Service Week. Glasgow, ca. 1933-1935 October 30 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 21)
  - "Germany", 1933 November (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 22)
  - "War-less World". Boston Peace Group, 1933 November (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 23)
  - "Students in Politics". Wellesley, 1933 November (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 24)
  - "Politics". Oxford, 1933 November 15 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 25)
  - "Some Aspects of European Situation". Episcopal Church, NY, 1933 November 12 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 26)
  - Untitled. International House, 1933 November 19 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 27)
  - "Christianity & Internationalism. I. The Present World Outlook". Toronto, 1934 January 27-1934 January 28 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 28)
  - "Universities & the Control of the World". Howard, 1934 February 02 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 29)
  - "ISS - an Educational Experiment". Wellesley Alumnae, 1934 February 08 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 30)
  - "Crisis of Christianity". Annual Dinner, Canadian Journal of Religious Thought, 1934 February 18 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 31)
  - "World Chaos faces Students". Montreal, 1934 February 19 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 32)
  - "True Internationalism". Toronto, 1934 February 22 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 33)
  - "Austria". Princeton, 1934 March 13 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 34)
  - "Students in Politics". Barnard, 1934 March 20 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 35)
  - "Can Education meet the fundamental needs of society?" Bouffémont, 1934 July 29 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 36)
  - "I. The Youth Movement in Europe: Victory and Defeat". Des Moines Public Forums, 1936 January 07-1936 February 15 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 37)
  - "II. Youth Without Work". Des Moines Public Forums, 1936 January 07-1936 February 15 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 38)
  - "III. The Daughters of the French Revolution". Des Moines Public Forums, 1936 January 07-1936 February 15 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 39)
  - "IV. England: Character and the Classics". Des Moines Public Forums, 1936 January 07-1936 February 15 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 40)
  - "V. Dictators in the Schoolroom". Des Moines Public Forums, 1936 January 07-1936 February 15 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 41)
  - "VI. The Control of Education and the Future of Europe". Des Moines Public Forums, 1936 January 07-1936 February 15 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 42)
  - "The fate of freedom of thought under European dictatorships". Omaha, 1936 February 02 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 43)
  - Untitled. Leiden, 1936 March 11 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 44)
  - Untitled, 1936 April 10 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 45)
  - "Need for a definite purpose in higher education". Smith, 1936 April 16 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 46)
  - "Students & policies". Roosevelt High School, 1936 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 47)
  - "I. National Unity: Does Uncle Sam really exist?" Des Moines Public Forums, 1936 November 09 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 48)
  - "II. American Education: Dream or Reality?" Des Moines Public Forums, 1936 November 12 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 49)
  - "Is Europe heading for war?" Junior Chamber of Commerce, Des Moines, 1936 November 19 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 50)
  - "III. Popular Government: Must it Prove a Myth?" Des Moines Public Forums, 1936 November 22 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 51)
  - "IV. How Secure is Life in America?" Des Moines Public Forums, 1936 November-1936 December (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 52)
  - "V. Is Europe heading for War?" Des Moines Public Forums, 1936 November-1936 December (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 53)
  - Untitled. NSFA Congress, 1936 December 28 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 54)
  - "Day of Prayer". Montreal, 1937 February 02 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 55)
  - "Appeal for German Christian Refugees". Providence, 1937 February 23 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 56)
  - "Numerous clauses & its implications". Smith, 1937 February 26 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 57)
  - "True Internationalism". Rotary, Edmonton, 1937 March 05 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 58)
  - Untitled. International Relations Club, Smith, 1937 May 18 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 59)
  - "The 2 Germanys. The social implications of German education under Hitler". Mt. Holyoke, 1937 May 13 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 60)
  - "U.S. & the New Alliances in Europe". Pendle Hill, 1937 May 23 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 61)
  - Untitled. Mt. Holyoke, Memorial Day, 1937 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 62)
  - "Mrs. Wooley Testimonial Dinner", [1937] (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 63)
  - "Challenge to Freedom of Thought". Mt. Holyoke Alumnae College, 1937 June 18 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 64)
  - "Some Aspects of the European Situation". Institute, Montreal, 1937 September 03 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 65)
  - "The Changing Social Order". Elgin House, 1937 September 10 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 66)
  - "Nationalism". Canadian Institute of International Affairs, Montreal, 1937 September 22 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 67)
  - "Basis for a New Peace Settlement". Pendle Hill, Dec. 1, 1937; Hartford, Apr. 6, 1938, Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 68)
  - "Can War be avoided?" Holyoke Rotary Club, 1938 January 11 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 69)
  - Untitled. Masters School, 1938 January 16 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 70)
  - "5 Million Refugees". Mt. Holyoke Chapel, 1938 January 19 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 71)
  - "Dictators in the School Room". Teachers Forum, Northampton, 1938 January 19 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 72)
  - "World in 30 Minutes!" YWCA, New Haven, 1938 February 04 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 73)
  - "The New Alliances in Europe (and the basis for a New Peace Settlement)". Omaha, 1938 February 13 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 74)
  - Grinnell College, 1938 February-1938 March (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 75)
  - "USSR: The Materialist Myth". Grinnell, 1938 March 01 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 76)
  - "Democracy in International Relations". Grinnell, 1938 March 15 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 77)
  - "The Passing of Austria". Mt. Holyoke, 1938 April 05 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 78)
  - "The Formation of Public Opinion". Mt. Holyoke Alumnae College, 1938 June 14 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 79)
  - "The Totalitarian Challenge to Democracy". Massachusetts State College, 1938 October 16 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 80)
  - "Is Democracy a Myth?" Hartford YMCA, 1938 October 19 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 81)
  - Untitled. Colby Junior College, 1938 November 18 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 82)
  - "Refugee Problem". Smith IRC, 1938 November 28 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 83)
  - "How Refugees are made & European attempts at a solution". Springfield FPA, 1939 January 11 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 84)
  - Untitled. Holyoke Workers Forum, 1939 January 24 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 85)
  - "Is a college education worthwhile?" Harvard, 1939 March 16 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 86)
  - "Peace and Learning". Phi Kappa Phi, Amherst, May 4, 1939; Mt. Holyoke, Memorial Day, 1939, Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 87)
  - "Education in the totalitarian state: a challenge". Mt. Holyoke Alumnae College, 1939 June 01 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 88)
  - "Education for Peace". Smith, 1939 October 09 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 89)
  - "America and the War in Europe". First Congregational Church, Holyoke, 1939 October 18 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 90)
  - "A Present-Day Peace Program for the United States". Friends Conference, NY, 1939 November 04 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 91)
  - "Do we want peace?" Smith, 1939 November 08 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 92)
  - Untitled. Thursday Luncheon Group, 1939 December 14 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 93)
  - "Education under the Dictators: A Challenge to America". Winsted, 1940 January 08 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 94)
  - "Education for Defense". 1st Congregational Church, Newton, 1940 January 09 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 95)
  - Untitled. Masters School, 1940 January 29 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 96)
  - "Education in the totalitarian countries". New York, 1940 February 17 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 97)
  - "Youth and Social Change". Cleveland, 1940 March 08 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 98)
  - Untitled. YWCA, Atlantic City, 1940 April 12 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 99)
  - "The Immigrant in America". Smith Alumnae College, 1940 June 20 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 100)
  - "The Redistribution of Human Talent". Harvard, 1940 July 03 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 101)
  - "1940 Appeal. Smith" / "1940 Appeal, Amherst & Mt. Holyoke", 1940 September 29 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 102)
  - "The Totalitarian Challenge to America". 2nd Congregational Church, Holyoke, 1940 October 04 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 103)
  - "Education in the Totalitarian Countries: A Challenge to Democracy". Boston Smith Club, 1940 October 14 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 104)
  - "Psychological Adjustment of Displaced People". AAUW, NY, 1940 October 21 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 105)
  - "Education for Defense". Massachusetts Association for Childhood Education, 1940 October 26 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 106)
  - "Roads to Peace". George School, Nov. 17, 1940; Masters School. Jan. 19, 1941, Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 107)
  - "The Current International Peace". Newton, Monday Afternoon, 1941 January 13 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 108)
  - "America & the War". Northfield Conference, 1941 January 29 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 109)
  - "Education for Defense, an Answer to Hitler's Challenge". Wellesley Community Forum, Feb. 2, 1941; College Club, Boston, Mar. 13, 1941, Undated (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 110)
  - Untitled. I.S.S., Smith, 1941 February 16 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 111)
  - "The Peace to Come". Smith, 1941 April 28 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 112)
  - "Why Education Failed in Europe: A Challenge to America". Brearley School, 1941 May 19 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 113)
  - "Can Education & Democracy Survive this War?" Harvard, 1941 July 22 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 114)
  - "The Struggle Between Peoples & Ideas". Cleveland, 1941 October 28 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 115)
  - "American Youth Faces Its Future". Hampshire Forum, 1941 November 02 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 116)
  - "Reconstruction of Education in Europe After the War". Smith Emergency Council, 1941 November 18 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 117)
  - "War, Peace and Us". Putney School, 1941 November 23 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 118)
  - "American Youth in a Fascist World". Brooklyn, 1941 December 11 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 119)
  - "The Crisis at Hand". Springfield Nurses, 1942 January 03 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 120)
  - Untitled. Masters School, 1942 January 18 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 121)
  - "Smith Little Chapel", 1942 February 24 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 122)
  - "The Transition from War to Peace". Smith, 1942 March 02 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 123)
  - "Strengthening Democracy in Wartime". Springfield Forum, 1942 April 07 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 124)
  - "A Strategy for American Youth". Classical High School, Springfield, 1942 June 09 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 125)
  - "Presuppositions of World Peace". Smith Alumnae, 1942 June 09 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 126)
  - "Education, Culture & Imperialism". ISSA, Washington, 1942 September 03 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 127)
  - "Intellectual Front". Univ. of Minnesota, 1942 October 08 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 128)
  - "Intellectual Cooperation & the League". WHYN, 1942 October 23 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 129)
  - "War on the Intellectual Front". NY Smith Club, 1942 November 06 (Box 11 (4-Manuscripts of speeches and lectures ), Folder 130)